<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Lumberj3ck website</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Lumberj3ck website</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 06 May 2024 12:46:04 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Uint and Int</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/uint-and-int/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 May 2024 12:46:04 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/uint-and-int/</guid>
      <description>In Go there a two types representing numbers (excluding floating point nubmers): uint and int. The maximum digital value you can store in int is 127. In uint is a 255. Here is why ⬇️&#xA;Every programming language saves numbers in Binary numbers&#xA;Int stands for all numbers positive and negative, when the uint in the opposite only for positive values from 0 to max_value.&#xA;So in int we spend one bit in front of every number for storing a sign of the number (1 for negative and 0 for positive).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Binary Numbers</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/binary-numbers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 May 2024 12:44:25 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/binary-numbers/</guid>
      <description>So basically each 1 or 0 in binary number means the power of 2&#xA;One&#xD;stand for yes and zero for No&#xD;. It means if this power of two is present inside of our number or not.&#xA;Lets build a 42 as the sum powers of 2:&#xA;32 + 8 + 2 = 42&#xA;32 is 2^5&#xA;8 is 2^3&#xA;2 is 2^1&#xA;The first right number in binary stands for 2 to power of 0 The second right number in binary stands for 2 to power of 1 &amp;hellip; In our example we don&amp;rsquo;t need 2^0 we need 2^1 this is second digit in binary number, but we don&amp;rsquo;t skip the first digit we just set it as 0.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Python Scope</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/python-scopes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 May 2024 11:36:52 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/python-scopes/</guid>
      <description>Learn how Python handles variables in different scopes. Avoid errors and write predictable code by understanding how functions access and modify variables.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Python Mutations</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/python-mutations/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2024 11:36:52 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/python-mutations/</guid>
      <description>Understand mutability in Python. Learn how variables can impact each other and how to manage these changes for predictable code. Covers lists, dictionaries, strings, and more.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
